<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Misc | Voulgaris.com Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.voulgaris.com/blog/categories/misc/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.voulgaris.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-08-22T21:50:18-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.voulgaris.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Constantino Voulgaris]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[My First Post]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.voulgaris.com/blog/2014/08/22/my-first-post/"/>
    <updated>2014-08-22T15:56:05-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.voulgaris.com/blog/2014/08/22/my-first-post</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>So this is my first post, of my first blog, of my first built-from-scratch-server. I originally built it up with <a href="https://ghost.org/">Ghost</a>, on my Rackspace virtual Ubuntu made from zero inspired by <a href="http://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2012/11/how-to-set-up-a-safe-and-secure-web-server/">this awesome series of Wired articles</a>.</p>

<p>Why get my hands &ldquo;dirty&rdquo; with Node.js, or scripts, or shells ? Just because it&rsquo;s harder.</p>

<p>I loved Ghost, but because our website at <a href="http://www.transactility.com">Transactility</a> is done in Rails, a few
front end stuff we&rsquo;ll be doing might involve Rails and Ruby, I decided to take a look at <a href="http://jekyllrb.com/">Jekyll</a> and <a href="http://octopress.org">Octopress</a></p>

<p>It&rsquo;s the way to learn about things and go back to my &ldquo;hacker&rdquo; (in the good sense), assembly language days of the Commodore 64. There are plenty of hosted solutions, Web based Blogspots, etc. but I liked the idea of installing everything from zero, be forced to use git more frequently, and feel a bit more of a hacker. Simple, concrete, just write in Markdown, type a few commands and publish it just by pushing to a git repo (I&rsquo;m using Heroku)</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>I&rsquo;ll keep my personal blog in Octopress for now, and will continue to develop a few apps and a site in Ruby/Rails (and Sinatra in one case), so thank you <a href="https://www.bloc.io/">Bloc.io</a>. I had an incredible learning experience with <a href="https://twitter.com/trybloc">Bloc.io</a>, and didn&rsquo;t put (yet) live any of my Rails projects nor sites as my primary objective was to get up to speed with modern frameworks and languages and to be capable of having a better ideas exchange with software developers.</p>

<p>I hope my future business interactions all work under the motto:</p>

<blockquote><p>Harder to learn, simpler to execute.</p></blockquote>

<p>Hope I can teach my kids that you can do things just because they are hard:</p>

<iframe width="420" height="315" src="//www.youtube.com/embed/6z1DidldxUo" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>


<p>And since I like bipartisanship ;), also remember this:</p>

<iframe width="560" height="315" src="//www.youtube.com/embed/xhYJS80MgYA" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>


<p>And to all my uruguayan friends, I say this:</p>

<iframe width="420" height="315" src="//www.youtube.com/embed/JLdA1ikkoEc" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
